<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="77" moduleid="437" modulename="page" contextid="702">
  <page id="77">
    <name>Build a lesson in the Online Lesson Planner</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Build your lesson in the online form and save to share with colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;The online &lt;a title="link to online LINCS lesson planner" href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/lesson-planner" target="_blank"&gt;Lesson Planner&lt;/a&gt; is a tool that allows you to build a full lesson, following the WIPPEA model and incorporating backward design. Instructions for using the Lesson Planner are included on the site. Create a lesson plan using your objective and incorporating formative assessment strategies.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Use the Lesson Planner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;Go to the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/lesson-planner" title="link to LINCS Lesson Planner site" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Lesson Planner&lt;/a&gt;. Click the&lt;strong&gt; Log In&lt;/strong&gt; menu link at the top right of the page. Log in using the same e-mail address and password as you use to access this course in the LINCS Learning Portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the &lt;b&gt;My LINCS&lt;/b&gt; page, choose &lt;b&gt;My Lesson Plans&lt;/b&gt; in the left navigation bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose &lt;b&gt;Add a Lesson&lt;/b&gt; and begin building your lesson. Save your lesson at the end of each section—Basic Information, Objectives, Resources, and so on—by scrolling to the bottom of the form and choosing &lt;b&gt;Save&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After you save a section, choose &lt;b&gt;Edit&lt;/b&gt; next the title of your lesson and continue building the lesson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After saving the completed lesson plan, &lt;b&gt;copy the URL link&lt;/b&gt; so you can share it with your facilitator as you submit the assignment. You can also print the lesson for us in your classroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Submit your Lesson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;Go back to the Effective Lesson Planning online course and find the assignment, The Lesson Planning Model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;At the bottom of the page, choose &lt;b&gt;Add submission&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Paste the URL link&lt;/b&gt; for the lesson plan you created into the Online text box. Add your one-page journal reflection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;Choose &lt;b&gt;Save changes &lt;/b&gt;at the bottom of the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;When you are finished with the assignment, choose &lt;b&gt;Submit assignment&lt;/b&gt; at the bottom of the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>2</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:1:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>25</revision>
    <timemodified>1540835511</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>