<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="75" moduleid="433" modulename="page" contextid="698">
  <page id="75">
    <name>Using a Rubric for Procedural Writing</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Rubrics can play an important role in helping learners monitor their performance on a writing task. They can also be used for peer review. See the resources here for examples of writing rubrics.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p align="left" style="text-align: left;"&gt;Rubrics can play an important role in helping learners monitor their performance on a writing task. They can also be used for peer review. See the resources below for examples of writing rubrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left" style="text-align: left;"&gt;Let’s use the example of &lt;span&gt;procedural writing&lt;/span&gt;, which provides the reader with written instructions or a “how-to” document for doing something. &lt;span&gt;Procedural writing &lt;/span&gt;must be clear, concise, and detailed enough to guide someone through the process that is being described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left" style="text-align: left;"&gt;To effectively communicate the process for doing something, &lt;span&gt;procedural writing&lt;/span&gt; must…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style="text-align: left;"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Clearly state a goal or objective.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;State why the task is interesting or important.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Provide an overview or list of materials or resources needed to perform the task.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Include all the steps for the task or procedure.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;State step-by-step instructions in proper sequence, leaving nothing out. It is helpful to use words such as first, next, then, finally….&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;The reader must be able to follow the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;procedural writing &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;without needing to make any assumptions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p align="left" style="text-align: left;"&gt;By teaching&lt;span&gt; procedural writing&lt;/span&gt;, instructors provide learners with the opportunity to write for an authentic purpose. To help students determine whether they have included all the elements required for effective &lt;span&gt;procedural writing&lt;/span&gt;, instructors can encourage them to use a rubric. When introducing the rubric, instructors should use a model essay that contains all the elements in the rubric. This will help learners see an example of effective &lt;span&gt;procedural writing&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left" style="text-align: left;"&gt;When teaching &lt;span&gt;procedural writing&lt;/span&gt;, instructors can do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style="text-align: left;"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Ask students to think of a simple task, one that they perform every day, such as fixing a bowl of cereal and banana for breakfast, making the bed, feeding the cat or dog, or addressing an envelope.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Ask students to write two or three sentences about the activity they have selected and why the task is an important or interesting. This becomes the introduction to their &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;procedural writing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; essay.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Now ask students to list the materials necessary to perform the task. For example, if they are explaining how to make a cup of tea, they will list a (tea)pot, water, a stove, a tea bag, a spoon, and a cup. The may also list sugar or honey, lemon, and/or milk, if they wish to include these in the description.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Have students write down in sequence each step necessary for completing the task.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Ask students to write a concluding statement describing how they can determine if the task was completed successfully.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Now ask each student to find a partner and trade papers with one another.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Ask students to critique each other's papers. This will require them to think critically about the instructions they are reading and to identify missing steps, if any. Ask them to use the rubric to determine if the papers have included all the elements of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;procedural writing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Now ask students to revise their papers, based on feedback from their partners.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Repeat this process over several class sessions, using other tasks until the students can use the rubric on their own to independently produce &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;procedural writing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p align="left" style="direction: ltr; text-align: left;"&gt;See the &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Procedural_Writing_Rubric.pdf" title="PDF - Opens in new window" target="_blank"&gt;sample procedural writing rubric&lt;/a&gt;. [Reprinted with permission from C. A. MacArthur &amp;amp; Z. A. Philippakos. (2012).&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt; College Writing: A Self-Regulated Strategy Approach.&lt;/span&gt; Unpublished curriculum.]&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>2</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:1:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>10</revision>
    <timemodified>1473965011</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>